Thomas Nathan Feeney

CONTACT DETAILS

Mobile: +447467944428

Email: <u>TNFeeney@hotmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomasfeeney/

Git: https://github.com/nathanfeeney

BACKGROUND

I have recently graduated from the University of the West of Scotland with a 2:1 Honours degree in Computing Science. During my time at university I worked with many languages and technologies including SQL, JavaScript and object oriented languages such as Java. In my final year I completed modules that were focussed on the analysis and capture of data, these modules were Data Warehouse Environments and Decision Support Systems. I have also completed a College Web Development course, where I gained great experience in working with SQL, PHP and HTML. I have learned to quickly pick up new languages and technologies. I have also completed many projects at University and College where organisation and planning were key in having a successful end product, many of which were completed using agile methodology.

I have had a number of customer facing roles where I have learned excellent communication skills and have developed my confidence. Examples of such roles include working as a sales assistant, bartending and working directly with a client in my Web Development role at Mates Rates Ltd.

EDUCATION

BSc (Hons) Computing Science - University of the West of Scotland - (Aug 2018 - June 2021), 2:1

At university I completed an honours degree in Computing Science, covering modules such as Advanced programming, Database Administration and Algorithms and Collections. Most of my classes have included a team work element which has greatly improved my communication and leadership skills.

HND in Web Development and Digital Design - New College Lanarkshire (Aug 2017 to June 2018), Grade B

Following on from my HNC worked with more advanced languages and frameworks such as JavaScript, JQuery, SASS and C#. I also worked with WordPress and furthered my experience with Excel.

HNC in Web Development and Digital Design - New College Lanarkshire (Aug 2016 to June 2017), Grade A

This was my first introduction to computing. In this course I was introduced to HTML, CSS and PHP. This was also a design course where I learned Photoshop. I also had an introduction to the Office365 package where I learned how to use software such as Excel and Word effectively.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, Java, C++, C#, SQL, UML

Technologies: Office365, Git, JQuery, WordPress, Android Studio, Windows, Unix/Debian9, Tableau

WORK EXPERIENCE

Website Developer Mates Rates Ltd - July 2020 to August 2020

In this role I built two websites using WordPress. During the development process I also gained experience using PHP and CPanel. This position has taught me the importance of organisation and planning ahead, it has also given me confidence in communicating with clients. I was also given an introduction to SEO through working with Google Analytics, Google Console and Google developer tools.

Sales Advisor Debenhams – April 2019 to August 2019

I worked within the click and collect team at Debenhams Glasgow where I was tasked with the organisation and distribution of parcels received in store. This was a fast paced position as there was very little time between receiving deliveries and customers arriving to collect their parcels. This became a high pressure job when deliveries were late as I had to remain calm and level minded whilst dealing with customers who had not received their parcels.

Bartender Two River Recruitment – June 2017 to April 2019

With Two River Recruitment I have worked at the Theatre Royal, King's Theatre and Glasgow Summer Sessions as a bartender. This role greatly improved my confidence, team working and communication skills. I learned to be assertive and remain composed as I had to use my judgement to decide when to stop serving customers alcohol.

Sales Assistant Lotus - January 2017 to January 2018

Lotus is a retail company that specializes in women's shoes where I worked as a sales assistant. In this job I was tasked with selling shoes to reach a target amount of sales each day. This meant approaching customers and promoting active sales and events. I was also tasked with producing a trade report for each day which involved calculating the total sales and discounts applied. I enjoyed working in a collaborative environment where we worked together to achieve our sales targets.

PROJECTS

Dissertation - BSc Honours Project

For my honours project I had the idea to create an application to discuss and implement a way that QR codes can be used to improve/benefit the hospitality sector. The main idea being that a restaurant can have a QR code that can be generated to link the user to a page on a web app that will display information to the user such as menus, deals and events. The web application was primarily created using PHP that allowed the connection to use SQL databases to store information relative to the user such as usernames and passwords.

Tank War - BSc Individual Project - Advanced Programming for Mobile Devices

This project involved building a game using Java and Android Studio. We were given parts of a Tank War game built in C# - our task was to recreate the game in Java and improve upon it. This project gave me experience developing a mobile app and modifying an existing codebase.

I'm Lost - BSc Group Project - Programming for Mobile Devices

I'm Lost is a web based dungeon crawler game made using Java, HTML, CSS and JavaScript. In this project I was made team leader and in charge of delegating tasks to the other members and making sure the work was to a desired standard. My task was to build the web page for the game, which I used HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript to do so. We presented our finished game to the year group as well as talking through our ideas and how we implemented them.

Other useful information

Full clean UK drivers licensce

References available upon request